{
    "id": "2707b905a5934fb099af8a9ac1806d98",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My mother ………………… in an insurance company.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "works",
                "is working",
                "work"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I usually …………………. up at 6 but today I …………………. up at",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about routines. The simple past is used to say that something happened at a certain point of time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "wakes, woke",
                "wake, woke",
                "woke, wake"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Turn on the lights. Change into passive.",
            "description": "We use let to turn imperatives into passive voice. ",
            "answers": [
                "The lights be turned on.",
                "Let the lights be turned on",
                "The lights be turn on."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He works …………………",
            "description": "There is no preposition before the expression abroad. ",
            "answers": [
                "abroad",
                "in abroad",
                "at abroad"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A/An …………………… is a person who does not believe in the existence of god.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "theist",
                "atheist",
                "pagan",
                "agnostic"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He has a deep love ………………… his country.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "of",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The government is inquiring ………………… the affairs of the company.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "on",
                "into"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She takes …………………… her elder sister.",
            "description": "To take after somebody is to resemble them.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "after",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………. him for a long time.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used with the meaning up to now. ",
            "answers": [
                "knew",
                "have known",
                "had known"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Abraham Lincoln abolished slavery. Replace abolish with a phrasal verb/idiomatic expression.",
            "description": "To put an end to something is to abolish it. ",
            "answers": [
                "put up with",
                "put an end to",
                "put out"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I always carry an umbrella …………………… it rains.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "in case",
                "if",
                "in case of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "To give someone a piece of your mind is to ……………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "praise them",
                "reprimand them",
                "express your love for them"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}